serif.com 2018-10-18

# Privacy Policy – Serif

Serif is a trading name of Serif (Europe) Ltd (“we”, “our” or “us”) registered in England number 2117968 with registered offices at: The Software Centre, 12 Wilford Ind Est, Nottingham NG11 7EP, UK. Telephone: UK - 0845 345 7770 Intl.- +44 115 914 2000.

This Privacy Policy, together with our Terms and Conditions, and any documents it references, set out the basis on which any Personal Data (as defined below) or which you provide to us will be processed by us as a result of using or interacting with the Serif.com website and its services (“Our Website”). We aim at all times to process and collect your data lawfully, transparently, fairly and without adversely affecting your rights as a Data Subject (as defined below). 

Please read the following carefully to understand our practices and procedures. We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. When we do we will update the “Last Updated” date. It is therefore important that you regularly review this Privacy Policy to ensure you are updated as to any changes.

### Definitions

In this policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:

**Data Protection Legislation:** up to but excluding 25 May 2018, the Data Protection Act 1998 and thereafter:

  1. unless and until the General Data Protection Regulation ((EU) 2016/679) (GDPR) is no longer directly applicable in the UK, the GDPR and any national implementing laws, regulations and secondary legislation, as amended or updated from time to time, in the UK; and then
  2. any successor legislation to the GDPR or the Data Protection Act 1998.

**Data Subject:** a natural identifiable person.

**Personal Data:** has the meaning set out in the Data Protection Legislation, being as at the data of this policy, any data which identifies a natural person (by way of example, name, address, phone number and so on).

### Who controls the Personal Data that is collected?

For the purpose of the Data Protection Legislation, the data controller and data processor is Serif (Europe) Ltd, a limited liability company registered in England with company number 2117968, whose registered offices at The Software Centre, 12 Wilford Ind Est, Nottingham NG11 7EP.

If you have any queries relating to our use of your personal information or any other related data protection questions, you can contact our nominated Data Protection Officer at [dataprotection@serif.com](mailto:dataprotection@serif.com) or write to us at Data Protection Officer, Serif (Europe) Ltd, 12 Wilford Ind Est, Nottingham NG11 7EP.

If you are not satisfied with any action taken by us or response given, you have the right to complain to Information Commissioner at [ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/), or help line telephone number: 0303 1231113.

In the event that Serif, its parent company or trading names and brands were subject to a change of ownership, the control and permissions that you have granted us with regard to your Personal Data will be transferred to the new owner.

### How do we collect Personal Data?

From 14th May 2018, we are no longer accepting new serif.com accounts. All sales are now processed via our new website [https://affinity.serif.com](https://affinity.serif.com/), and will require an account to be created during the checkout process. Our Affinity site has its own terms and conditions and privacy policy governing how we collect and use your Personal Data, which you can read here:

Existing account holders can still access and update their Personal Data by logging in to their account on Our Website.

We do still collect a small amount of data from you when you use Our Website. This data is essential in helping us to provide an excellent overall experience for our customers when working with Serif and for helping us to continually improve that experience.

The data we collect is as follows:

  * When you visit our Web Site, we use cookies (see below for more information about cookies) to collect web site usage information such as the type and version of browser and operating system you use. Cookies are not used to store personal details such as your name and address.
  * We may use “image tracking” to ascertain whether you do or do not read our email communications.
  * If you: (a) complete one of our enquiry forms on Our Website; (b) enter into a contract with us for our services; (c) report a problem with Our Website; or (d) otherwise correspond with us, we may collect your name, address (including e-mail address), other contact details, phone numbers, identification and bank details.

### Why do we process and store your Personal Data?

We will only ever collect and use your Personal Data in accordance with Data Protection Legislation. Our grounds for processing your Personal Data are as follows:

  * **Consent**

In some cases, we will process your Personal Data based on obtaining your express consent for us to do so. Where this applies, we will always offer you the opportunity to withdraw your consent for this processing at any time.

  * **Contract**

It may be necessary for us to capture and store your Personal Data to fulfil our contractual obligation to you. For example, we may need to retain a copy of your details for the duration of any subscription services you purchase from us.

  * **Legitimate Interest**

Under the EU General Data Protection Regulation there is a concept of "legitimate interests" as a justification for processing your Personal Data, where we have good and fair reasons to do so in ways which do not adversely affect your interests and rights.

We sometimes need to collect and process your Personal Data to pursue our legitimate interests in line with running our business, but will always do so in a fair and reasonable way that does not materially impact your interests, rights or freedoms.

Our legitimate interests for processing your Personal Data are:

    * To enable you to access and use Our Website and your account, to provide access to your order history and any products / product keys you’ve purchased, and to provide support.
    * To provide a personalised experience on Our Website. For example, we may use your locale data to display localised content and pricing on our product pages.
    * To notify you of changes or enhancements to our services, such as changes to Our Website or your account, and any new offers, products or services that may be of interest to you. We will always offer you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving further non-essential emails from us.
    * To detect and prevent fraud and abuse of Our Website, and to help keep our services secure.
    * To improve the quality of your experience on Our Website. We are always working to improve Our Website and our products, and may use certain demographic information such as your account country and language preference to help us achieve this.

### Where do we store Personal Data?

#### Website Data

We store all Personal Data collected via Our Website on secure servers located in the United Kingdom. We may also store some of your details on our Affinity database, which is administered by Amazon and located in the Republic of Ireland (ROI).

#### Email Communications

Some of our email communications are administered through MailChimp ([www.mailchimp.com](https://mailchimp.com/)), and we may store some of your Personal Data - including your name, email address and contact preferences - on a MailChimp server. Mailchimp may process and store your data outside the EEA.

MailChimp is a U.S. based company and is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield framework. For more information, see [MailChimp’s Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

### Do we share Personal Data?

We will not share your Personal Data with third parties without having obtained your consent. We will only disclose your Personal Data, without your consent or without notice, if required to do so by law or if in good faith we believe that such action is necessary to:

  * Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on us.
  * Protect and defend our lawful rights and property.
  * Act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of our customers and the public.

### How can you gain access to your Personal Data?

You can access your Personal Data by logging into your account on Our Website. Your account allows you access to your order history, view product keys associated with your purchases, and access your associated Personal Data.

You can also request and obtain details of the Personal Data we may hold about you by emailing us at [dataprotection@serif.com](mailto:dataprotection@serif.com), or writing to us at the following address:

Data Protection Officer  
Serif  
12 Wilford Ind Est  
Nottingham  
NG11 7EP

When contacting us, please quote your name and email address. We would be grateful if you could also provide brief details of the information required as this will help us to accurately respond to your request.

For the protection of all our customers, we will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any Personal Data we may hold about you.

We will to respond to all such requests within 30 days.

### How can you make changes to your Personal Data?

If you find that that any of the Personal Data we hold for you is incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to request that we rectify these errors.

You can make changes to your Personal Data via your account on Our Website.

You can also request we update your Personal Data by emailing [dataprotection@serif.com](mailto:dataprotection@serif.com). Please include as much detail as possible regarding the changes you wish to make, as this will help us in dealing with your request.

We will respond to all such requests within 30 days.

### Your right to be forgotten

You can request that we delete your account and any Personal Data we have collected from you by emailing us at [dataprotection@serif.com](mailto:dataprotection@serif.com). Please provide your name and email address to help us with your request. Please note that we may not be able to delete your data if we are obliged to retain it to fulfil a legal or statutory obligation.

Please be aware that once deleted, your account will no longer be accessible and cannot be restored so you should ensure that anything that is accessed via your account that you wish to keep is backed up before proceeding.

We will respond to all such requests within 30 days.

### How secure is your Personal Data?

We recognise that people are increasingly concerned about the protection of Personal Data from misuse and abuse, and about privacy in general. We constantly review and enhance our technical, physical and managerial procedures in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of Personal Data in order to protect it from unauthorised access, accidental loss and/or destruction.

Where necessary, we use industry standard 128-bit secure sockets layer (SSL) technology to encrypt sensitive data.

It is important for you to remember to protect yourself against unauthorised access by guarding your password. For example, if you use a shared computer, make sure you logout or close your browser whenever you leave the computer.

### Do we transfer Personal Data overseas?

The Internet is a global environment. Using the Internet to collect and process Personal Data involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Although the data we collect from you is stored in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), data transferred to third parties to perform our contract may be transferred to third parties outside the EEA. By browsing Our Website and communicating with us you acknowledge and agree that your Personal Data may be transferred overseas. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

### Do we monitor and/or record communications?

Monitoring or recording of your calls, emails, and other communications may take place in accordance with UK law, and in particular for business purposes, such as for quality control and training, and in order to prevent or detect crime. Please visit the following website for further information: [ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/).

### Children

We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from anyone under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 and believe he or she has disclosed Personal Data to us, please contact us at [dataprotection@serif.com](mailto:dataprotection@serif.com).

Where processing of Personal Data is based on consent, if we learn that this data belongs to someone under the age of 13, we will cease processing and will take reasonable measures to delete the applicable data from our records, unless the consent is provided by a parent or guardian.

## Cookies

**Cookie Law:** means the relevant parts of the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

**Cookie:** A cookie is a small text file that is placed on to your computer via your web browser when you visit a website. Cookies are used to save certain information and are only used to store data. They are not used to do anything harmful like start a process or infect your computer.

### What Cookies do we use?

There are number of Cookies that are stored as soon as you visit our website. All Cookies used by Serif (Europe) Ltd on Our Website are used in accordance with current Cookie Law. Some are from us and are necessary for certain functions of the website, and others are from by third-party websites such as Facebook.

Before Cookies are placed on your computer or device you will be shown a cookie compliance statement, requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies you are enabling us to provide you with the best possible experiences and services to you. You may wish to deny consent to the placing of the Cookies at which point we request you cease using Our Website.

### Cookies used on Our Website

  * SessionID
  * Serif_Country
  * Serif_Customer
  * Serif_Db
  * Serif_International
  * Serif_MCCode
  * Serif_UID
  * Serif_AcceptPhotoPlus

### Third-party cookies

There are a few third-party websites who also use cookies on our behalf. Social Networking sites, like Facebook, use Cookies so you can easily share content. Google Analytics saves anonymous statistical data that we use to improve your experience on our site. We do not directly control these Cookies. You can check the third-party websites for more information on these.

  * Google Maps and Analytics: [Google Privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_uk/policies/privacy/)
  * Facebook: [Facebook privacy policy](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)
  * Twitter: [Twitter Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)
  * StumbleUpon: [StumbleUpon Privacy Policy](http://www.stumbleupon.com/privacy)

### Removing Cookies

Cookies don’t stay around forever and your web browser will eventually delete them. When a website stores a Cookie, it states how long the cookie should stay on the computer for – this can be for the current visit only or for a period of time, for example one week. Our main Cookie SessionID only stays on your computer while you are on Our Website. It is automatically removed when you leave Our Website.

You can choose to delete our, or any website’s, Cookies from your web browser at any time (for help on how to do this, go to [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/)). You can also set your web browser to not accept any Cookies if you wish. You will still be able to view Our Website, but some of the personalised features may not work correctly.

## Questions

If you have any questions about our Privacy and Cookies Policy, please [get in touch](https://affin.co/contactus).

_Last Updated: 21st May 2018_
